



Omkar Pathak

Date of birth: 01/10/1985 | Nationality: Indian | Gender: Male | Phone

number: (+91) 9730473226 (Mobile) | Email address: omcarpathak@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omkar-pathak-9464647b/

Skype: omkarpathak1 | **Address:** Pune, India (Home)

About me:

ISTQB Certified tester with 12+ years of diversified experience in Software Testing field. Currently working as **Quality Assurance Lead** in Harbinger Systems Pvt. Ltd and responsible for **Automation Testing, Manual Testing and Test Management.** Experience in different tools - Selenium, Azure DevOps, CI / CD, LamabaTest, etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

17/12/2012 - CURRENT Pune, India

OUALITY ASSURANCE LEAD HARBINGER SYSTEMS PVT. LTD.

- Responsible for all the automation testing for all the applications
- Automation testing using Selenium Web Driver using Data Driven and Keyword Driven Framework
- Designed and implemented generic and optimized way of Automation using Lightening Check and Katalon tool
- Writing and executing automation scripts through Lightening Check **Java and Selenium** based Hybrid framework
- Parallel Execution of automation scripts for different applications on Desktop and Mobile
- Leading testing team of 20+ people from different modules making sure all are following QA processes
- Focusing on quality deliverables in each sprint
- Experience in Functional Testing, System Testing, API Testing, Web Application testing, Mobile Testing
- Generating different test scenarios by applying ECP, BVA testing techniques
- Implemented CI/CD in Azure DevOps with Lightening Check Automation tool
- Exposure to Security Testing OWASP vulnerabilities and Basic knowledge of performance testing

27/07/2010 - 14/12/2012 Pune, India

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER EVOLVEWARE TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD.

- · Analyzing complex conversion requirement document
- Writing and executing test cases
- Logging & tracking bugs in BugTracker.NET
- Testing of the product includes Functional Testing, Cross browser Testing, Integration testing, Regression testing, Database Testing, etc.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/07/2007 - 04/2009 Pune, India

MASTERS IN COMPUTER MANAGEMENT

Address Pune, India

07/07/2003 - 15/04/2006 Pune, India

BACHELOR OF COMMERCE

Address Pune, India

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): MARATHI

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
GERMAN	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Software Testing | Automation Testing | System Testing | Integration Testing | Smoke Testing | Sanity Testing | Selenium | Selenium WebDriver | Azure DevOps | Jira | Regression Testing | Defect Management | SQL | Java | Python | Agile | API Testing | Software Testing Life Cycle | Git | Azure | Docker | User Acceptance Testing | TestNG | Azure CI/CD | Manual Testing | Functional Testing | Linux | Maven | Postman

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/10/2011

ISTQB Foundation Level Exam – International Software Testing Qualifications Board Indian Testing Board - Reg. No. ITB0004684

05/09/2015

Champion Defect Finder - Harbinger Systems Pvt. Ltd.

15/05/2014

Individual Award - Excellence in Quality Assurance - Harbinger Systems Pvt. Ltd.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Automobiles, Travelling